# Dliver Diamond

I am a full-stack developer with many years programming experience across many languages and technologies. Recently I have been developing FX services for HSBC's commercial corporate payments application (JS, Clojure, Java).

I'm passionate about: ES6, Lisps & functional programming; Linux architecture; and approaches that emphasise devops, fast delivery, clean code, & developer anarchy.

# **Background**

I have been programming since I was 13 - building web MMORPGs with friends (HTML & PHP) with 1000s of players. At university (2:1 Physics) I spent 2 years programming a bio-ecosystem simulation (C++). I have worked in politics, film production, TV & theatre development, and finance. I pushed and built tech solutions in all of these industries from simple web apps (Node, Python, Ruby), to finance analysis apps (Java). I trained myself at a top dev bootcamp, focussing on professional full-stack skills and modern methodologies.

Recently at HSBC, our small team brought modern disciplines to a heavily regulated corporate environment. We demonstrated the benefits of devops, agile, continuous delivery, microservice architectures, constant retrospection and developer freedom, whilst always focussing on releasing value to clients.

## **Skills**

## **Programming:**

- JavaScript (ES6, Node, Express, Dojo, JQuery, RxJS, Selenium) 6+ yrs
- Clojure (Compojure) 1+ yrs
- Java (Android, Spring) 2+ yrs
- Ruby (Rails) 1yr
- C++ 3+ yrs
- Python
- HTML, HTML5, CSS, LESS
- DB (MySQL PostgreSQL, Mongo)

## Delivery/Ops:

- Continuous Delivery (Jenkins, TeamCity,
- Version control: Git, RTC
- Linux (Redhat, Debian, Ubuntu)
- Rash
- Networking (DNS, TCP/IP, HTTPS)
- Eclipse, Intelli], Android Studio (though I MVC Architectures prefer a text editor where possible)

# Methodologies:

- Devops (Fast release cycles)
- Agile (lots of retrospecting)
- Test Driven Development
- Behaviour Driven Development
- Pairing
- Microservices Architectures

## Other Expertise

Government: I have 8 years experience across Government, public policy, and the digital & creative industries. I continue to support a political network for those sector.

Finance: Aside from my work in HSBC's FX department, I have also worked in a credit trading hedge fund, a Chinese event-driven brokerage, and a corporate finance boutique (analysing media and tech opportunities).

Communications: I have worked on public policy campaigns, political communications, and film & theatre marketing.

# **Work History**

# HSBC GFX (Dec 2017 - Sept 2017) | DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

We delivered a suite of microservices in Clojure and ES6 and interfacing them with a legacy Java6 / dojo.js monolith.

Our team of 6 worked from within the modernising agile-embracing GFX department of the investment bank, but worked to bring their products into HSBCnet, one of the world's most used commercial payment applications.

I worked in a mordern coding environment: devops, daily release cycles, developer anarchy, microservices, test-driven development and client behaviour driven development, with an ability to write code and have it in production in the same day. However I simultaneously worked on the HSBCnet application, being developed on a quarterly release cycle, with manual testing, and old SDLCs.

# Makers Consultants (Dec 2015 - Present) | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CONSULTANT

I was involved from the beginning in Makers Academy's Consultancy arm. I have remit to work on Makers' educationbased platform when not with a corporate partners (HSBC, Tek Systems, & Allegis Group).

# Bob & Co (Nov 2014 - May 2016) | HEAD OF DIGITAL AND COMMUNICATIONS

A small media (film, TV, theatre) developer, and financier. I ran the technological, research & communication efforts. I also built (and maintained) the company website, and other applications (Java & JS) for their partners & subsidiaries.

I later became Acting Director of Operations during a staff maternity leave, tasked with extensive audit and efficiency

efforts in the IT, telecoms, and other office admin budgets.

#### SUMS Film & Media (Aug 2015 - Dec 2015) | DIGITAL & TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

An independent film producer. I advised the chief executive on their projects' digital strategies (see IMDB). I worked on various applications, including marketing websites (PHP & HTML5).

Office of the Digital & Cultural Minister (Nov 2008 - Nov 2014) | SENIOR PARLIAMENTARY ADVISOR I managed the Parliamentary office of Rt. Hon. Ed Vaizey MP from the date of his Ministerial appointment. I oversaw the running of the office, interviewing, training and managing all junior staff. I worked on campaigns such as improving Wifi provision in public libraries and bringing coding into the national curriculum.

Aside from working on digital & media policy, I was given a wide remit and free-reign within the office, so I often used programmed office solutions, developing wordpress applications (*PHP*) for websites and databasing, and MS access applications for automating emails and training.

#### North Square Blue Oak (Jan 2014 - Mar 2014) | SABBATICAL ANALYST

A brokerage and corporate finance boutique, assessing new corporate finance opportunities in the digital sectors. The company drew heavily on my technological expertise in assessing potential investments.

**CQS Asset Management (Feb 2013 - Mar 2013)** | *MARGINS DEPT ANALYST & DEVELOPMENT INTERN*A \$13bn credit hedge fund: in liability management analysis with collateral specialists (creating an app to assess marginal risks); and also with the strategic IT team, developing an (credit price monitor) application (*C#*).

# **Education**

## Makers Academy (May 2016 - Aug 2016)

Makers Academy afforded me the opportunity to learn professional best practices, surrounded by some truly great programmers. I developed my curiosity and hungry passion for code, with focus on becoming an independent learner and problem-solver. They offer a firm grounding in the principles of software craftsmanship: OOP, TDD, SOLID, BDD.

#### Physics 2:1 (BSc & ARCS): Imperial College London (Oct 2005 - July 2008)

I focussed on computational simulations, astrophysics, plasma physics, and the practicalities of nuclear fusion energy as a future energy source.

#### Final Year Degree Project (C++)

I received 93% for an computer simulation investigation into the process of evolution. I wrote the program from scratch, modelling biological systems. I was praised particularly for analysing great amounts of data, spotting patterns and anomalies, presenting them accessibly and quantifying the results in a manner that the department had never seen before.

## **Interests**

#### CACIN - The Political Creative Industries Network (2008 - 2017) | DIRECTOR

I developed and maintained relationships with many key players in the tech & creative sectors, and ran regular panels and drinks receptions across the UK, centering on issues from the digital single market to diversity in the media.

**The Digital Bazaar, Tate South Lambeth Library (2009 - 2013)** | FOUNDING VOLUNTEER & IT EXPERT Taught basic computer, smartphone and other technology use to struggling members of the Lambeth community (many of whom did not have English as a first language). Runners-up for the CILIP Libraries Change Lives Award 2012.

## Other:

**Tech Tinkering** – I'm a Linux user at home (Fedora, Debian, Ubuntu, Mint). I have a home-made NAS made with a Raspberry Pi, and a homemade server – also running on Raspbian. I code small apps (usually in ES6 now) and run them from that server.

**Music** - I have an extensively musical education. I received the music scholarship to my secondary school. I sang in a Christ Church Cathedral Choir Oxford, and played the Saxophone, Violin, Piano, and guitar.

Tennis - I play regularly with a variety of partners and am coached professionally.

**Cooking** - I love cooking and spend a great deal of time in the kitchen. My recipes are popular on Instagram.